

# **Front-End Developer**

864-449-7072 frazierr2@gmail.com ThinkFrazier.com github/frazierr2

# **Objective**

I am a Front-End Developer with over 7 years' experience in multiple areas of the technology field and over 2 years' experience in full-time Web Development. Passionate about shaping the future of the web, I am seeking a position that will allow me to create web apps and websites that are geared to the end user. I strive to understand the user who will be using the application inside and out to provide a clean and positive experience.

### RELEVANTSKILLS

#### LANGUAGE AND PRACTICES

HTML5

CSS3/SCSS

JavaScript (ES5 and ES6)

Git

**JSON** 

**AJAX** 

RESTful API's

Github / Bitbucket

PHP

**SQL** 

#### FRAMEWORKS AND LIBRARIES

React / Vue

Backbone JS/Underscore JS

Bootstrap / UI Kit

jQuery

Laravel

## **CURRENT PROJECT**

Over the last few months, I have transitioned to a Full Stack Developer with Jackson Furniture. With a few full stack apps under my belt, I have been developing tools and reports for internal departments to cut cost, run more efficiently and complete more task.

Outside of work, I have been leveling up with PHP, SQL and other backend technologies so that I can continue to develop and grow as a full stack developer.

## **EDUCATION**

### Front-End Engineering

The Iron Yard, September 2016 - December 2016

**Bachelors of Science in Business** 

Administration and Sociology

Winthrop University, August 2004 - May 2009

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Front-End Developer**

#### Jackson Furniture July 2017 - present

- Complete redesign and overhaul of Jackson Furniture's website using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript to create a responsive site for any device that you are on.
- During redesign, used AJAX to communicate to a PHP Laravel backend to bring all products and data into view from a SQL/DB2 databases.
- Work with PHP and Python teams to create and manage web apps for internal user teams and for our external dealer portals.
- Refactor and reduce existing code base from 12 companywide sites down to three across all platforms.
- Develop backend code in Laravel to handle and manipulate data.
- -Starting to transition frontend to Vue.js

### **Front-End Developer**

MedProcure, LLC

March 2017 - July 2017

- Contracted to design, develop and implement the front end of their new Supply Chain Management Software.
- Combining HTML5, CSS3, Vanilla JavaScript and jQuery, I created the front end for their meal planning application where schools can offer to parents as a nutritional resource.
- Using AJAX, I communicated with a PHP Backend to pull in all data to view and manipulate based on user interaction.